Okay. So far you've learned about the importance of
Ok到目前为止 我们已经学习了分散化投资的重要性
diversification and how to calculate portfolio mean and variance.
以及如何计算投资组合均值和方差
You may wonder, what are the best ways to assign to each stock in your portfolio.
你可能会疑问 如何最有效地将资金分配给投资组合中的每支股票
Before we dive into portfolio optimization,
在深入讲解投资组合优化之前
let's take a look at the set of all possible portfolios.
先看看所有可能的投资组合集合
This will lead us to an important concept, the efficient frontier.
这就要引出一个重要的概念 即有效边界
Before we start, let's quickly recap.
在开始前 先简单回顾下几个概念
The expected return of a portfolio,
投资组合的预期收益率
equals the weighted sum of each stock's expected returns.
等于每支股票的预期收益率加权和
The variance of a portfolio,
投资组合的方差
equals the sum of the pairwise covariances weighted by the products of the weights.
等于配对协方差与权重的积之和
Okay. I think we're ready to go.
Ok可以继续学习了
Let's first take a look at a simple example with five stocks.
先从一个简单的例子开始 其中包含五支股票
Stocks A, B, C,
A、B、C、D 和 E
D and E with given annual mean returns and covariances.
分别具有特定的年度均值收益率和方差
One day your manager gives you $10,000 and tells
有一天 经理给了你 10,000 美元
you to invest in these five stocks whichever way you want.
并且告诉你随意投入这五支股票
But taking only long not short positions.
但只能做多 不能做空
What would you do with this money?
你会如何投资这笔钱？
Of course, you would want to impress your manager and create
当然 你肯定希望创建一个收益率最高 风险最低的投资组合
a portfolio with the highest returns and the lowest risk.
让经理对你留下好印象
Is this possible?
可行吗？
How would you do it? You've given the task some thought and
如何创建？你思考了一段时间
decided to just create a few portfolios with randomly assigned weights.
决定创建几个投资组合并随机分配权重
For the first portfolio,
对于第一个投资组合
you give each stock an equal weight of 20% of the total capital.
将每支股票的权重设为 20%
The portfolio return equals 4% and the standard deviation equals 3%.
投资组合的收益率为 4% 标准差为 3%
Is this good enough?
这个结果很好了吗？
You are not sure.
你不确定
So, you just keep testing different combinations by assigning a little more weight to
所以你不断测试不同的组合
one stock and a little less to another and
每次都使某支股票的权重高一点 另一个的权重低一点
then rechecking the portfolio's return and risk.
然后检查投资组合的收益率和风险
The more simulations you do,
模拟的次数越多
the more interesting the problem gets.
问题变得越来越有趣
For example, both scenario one and two have the same risk,
例如 情形 1 和情形 2 的风险一样
but scenario one has higher expected return.
但是情形 1 的预期收益率更高
In this case, you will definitely prefer scenario one.
所以你肯定会选情形 1
Also, scenario four has the highest expected return
此外 情形 4 的预期收益率最高 为 0.07
of 0.07 but it also has the highest risk of 0.04.
但是风险也最高 为 0.04
Scenario four is less attractive because it is a riskier portfolio.
情形 4 不太吸引人 因为它的风险更高
This is interesting; isn't it?
这很有趣 对吧？
Let's try to run thousands more scenarios and plot the
我们模拟下数千个情形
expected portfolio return against portfolio volatility.
并画出预期投资组合收益率与波动性图形
Okay. Here is a plot representing 25,000 simulated portfolios.
Ok这是一个表示 25,000 个模拟投资组合的图形
Each dot represents a possible risk return combination
每个点都代表这组股票能够产生的
that can be generated by the basket of stocks.
一种潜在风险-收益率组合
The x axis is the volatility and the y-axis is the return.
X 轴表示波动性 Y 轴表示收益率
What have you noticed? Let's take a look at a quick example.
你发现了什么？我们来看一个示例
Let's take a look at these two portfolios represented by the red and yellow dots.
看看红点和黄点表示的两个投资组合
Notice that both portfolios have the same risk of 0.035 but
这两个投资组合的风险都是 0.035
the red portfolio has significantly higher expected return of 0.06.
但是红色投资组合的预期收益率高多了 为 0.06
Furthemore, the red dot outperforms
并且 红点比风险为 0.035 的
all the portfolios with risk of 0.035 but there's more.
所有其他投资组合业绩都要好 还要更多这样的点
Have you noticed that all the dots that lie on
你注意到了上边界上的所有点
the upper boundary outperform the dots below it?
都比这些点下面的点业绩要好吗？
This is the efficient frontier.
这就是有效边界
The efficient frontier is the upper boundary of the set of possible portfolios.
有效边界是指一组潜在投资组合的上边界
Portfolios on this boundary have the maximum achievable return for a given level of risk.
对于给定风险级别来说 在此边界上的投资组合能够实现的收益率最高
Any portfolios above the frontier are unachievable.
任何高于此边界的投资组合都无法实现
It's not possible to find a combination of stocks that
无法找到风险相同
produces a higher level of return at that same level of risk.
但是收益率更高的股票组合
On the flip side, portfolios below the frontier
另一方面 低于该边界的投资组合肯定能实现
are certainly achievable but one might wonder why
但是你可能会疑问
a rational investor would prefer a lower rate of return when she
为何理性投资者会选择一个收益率更低的投资组合
could achieve a higher return while taking on the same level of risk.
而不去选择在相同风险水平下 收益率更高的投资组合
The portfolio that achieves the lowest level of
达到最低风险水平的投资组合
risk is called the minimum variance portfolio,
称为最小方差投资组合
and the portfolios on the efficient frontier are known as market portfolios.
位于有效边界的投资组合称为市场投资组合